the experience of other of another
person your experience of another as I
said it's true it's correct to say oh
yes that's the experience of your five
Aggregates but if that experience of
another is not seen as an image
correctly independent of space and time
that phenomenon is not seen
peripherally it will imply that there is
also the internal experience of
others at their counterpart that you are
not privy to and that's already outside
of your agregate assumption and that's
why self exists internally or externally
for that
matter so the self will the sense of
self or the
conceit for a for for AR saaka who is
free from atav but he still is not free
from his self-centeredness to varing
various degrees that also implies a certain
degrees that also implies a certain
perception of private self-centeredness
of
others private conceit that he's not as
I said that he cannot access but it's
there but then if he starts seeing that
as an
image that's how it the the the emphasis
gets undone the image Remains the Same
the phenomenon Remains the Same the
design ation Remains the Same but what
it implies
changes and that's
important well as a practice obviously
because if you do it like that then see
if like if somebody who is still very
much assumes the internal of their
experience here and now you know is mine
and doesn't matter whether they take
scientific view or mystical view or
whatever if they're seeing they're on
out of other still there when you tell
them that experience of another is just
an image they're going to assume aha so
others are just in me here right here in
this space and time of me and that's
like solipsism but the dumb I've done
solipsism but the dumb I've done
rightly others are not in you more than
you are in them from your point of view
so in other words when you cease to
be self for yourself here
to that extent other selves out there
will also cease to be
selves so it's not just that others are
not in you even you is not in
you but obviously somebody who is still
on the level of me here um sense of self
atada anything any information like this
they will not see the Nuance difference
and they would just it just sounds like
solipsism it just sounds like
everybody's in me my perception is what
everybody is there is no real everybody
this is only what I perceive was like
but that's undermined by the sense of
self assuming
internally and if you were to approve
that they will cease to be in you so to
speak they will be neither neither here
nor there nor between the two as as
actually Bak says won't be in them yeah
and that's why if if like in case of an
Arun as I said um that's where his
confidence comes
from that's why he doesn't tremble
amidst any of assembly
not because he's not percipient that
there are many people around him but
it's because one or thousand people
there are no assumed private internal
Dimension that has a view of me that I
cannot access that which undermines my
sense of me gone he sees that as a
peripheral image neither here nor there
if he thinks about his own self-center
in regard to others he thinks about that
as a peripheral image neither here nor
there as a phenomenon independent of
space of time so there can be no more
fear towards others no more anger
towards others no more lasting after
others uh and as I said uh when we
started talking you could see that's
exactly you could you could even imagine
that you could get a you could get a
taste of that how relieved like imagine
you live in a crowd at home where where
everything everything is like
seen everything you do everything you
say is cont constantly basically paired
uh with with with eyes of others and
Company and thoughts and so on and all
of that carries that external point of
view to me that I don't have control of
and that's why I feel undermined and shy
or irritated or just just tired or
whatever and imagine now they all
disappear and you just feel alone and
you're going to feel relief cuz it's
just you with yourself to the extent
that you are
no more no less and then just sit and
put your feet up and you just feel nice
cuz there is nobody there just just
having their input having their presence
of that external kind that fundamentally
it's unpleasant and that's what like was
describing the being for others and it's
always out of my hand that's why my
being how do you put it my being kind of
gets taken from me in a sense into that
Dimension and you feel that but you're
not saying it there's nice poetic almost
description of the fact but he couldn't
see the way out but the way out is that
that you assume is there outside
internal Dimension is another phenomenon here and
Dimension is another phenomenon here and
there another another phenomenon another
image another dharm independent of space
in time that which you assume as the
internal behind all these senses in me
same so contemplate things internally
contemplate things externally there will
be no room for self to hide cuz self
requires that internal
Dimension assumed implication whether
that Dimension is at the counterpart of
me or others it doesn't matter it's
external to the experience as a
whole so people animals brahmas dasas
maras for an
Arun no internal Dimension assumed that
is outside of him given footing to exist
through his through his um misconception
of his
images in regard to those things it's
all simple what it is and that's why
he's unshakable so not misconceiving images
unshakable so not misconceiving images
yep Imaging Imaging Imaging just T yeah
but images as I said images is what you
find at the back of your mind in regard
to things not what you kind of think oh
this is an imor
yeah yeah this doesn't dist Discerning
images
M as images well Discerning images IM
and like as we spoke in the other um
recent talk the group talk we had here
it's like so do do you think images are
in your
head and usually that's usually the the
first thing people be think which means
that's the first thing you have to start
undoing so when images cease to be in
your head images of others that imply
their personal their being independent
of you will cease to be placed in them
it will be seen as a phenomenon it's
neither here nor
there yeah neither here
good non locality yeah so you could see
like the practicality of
Bak he was not just like a philosophical
statement or a logical hey let me let me
provide you a system of seen and heard
and how all connects all the dots no you
see it like that rightly you will be
neither here there nor between the two
nor anybody will be anything neither
there nor here nor between the
two and he
an simply an account of that
understanding
that any it sounds you know like this
room is empty of self this place is
empty of self but anything pertaining to
self and that's how it's like he enters
into that
emptiness or there's
nothing belong there's nothing belonging
to me anywhere anywhere world yeah
exactly it's basically the same kind of
it's exactly yeah it Paints the same it
sets up the same um
images yeah IM contemplation sets sets
up the same sort of recognition
that then you need to as I said sustain
and um maintain in a sense of of uh
until it until it permeates all the
subtle aspects all the subtler implications
aspects all the subtler implications
suler yeah where are where are others
for you now where's your mother where's
your father yeah you you look at the dog
now job where where is he now is he in
that lamp of of of of Flesh you know
coated with a fur blanket is is he
inside there why would you assume that
Oho is he in me then or you realize all
these thoughts means you still give
priority to he somewhere and you don't
see that as an
image and the point is you can't see it
as an image once or twice for that
assumption to to to to drain away you
need to keep seeing it you need to keep
catching yourself each time which means
you need to have faith in this
instruction cuz if you don't have faith
in instruction I tell you you look at it
once and you don't see it as an image I
see it it has to be somewhere I mean
it's a fact how can he be here if he's
not somewhere how can what what am I
perceiving if he's not somewhere and
then you're going to dismiss it but if
you repeat it sufficient amount of time
seeing as an image you recognize oh crap
it is an
image independent of space and time it's
not in me it's not in
him it's
there likewise your likewise anything
that has a nature to
appear self anything
anything and that's when it ceases to be
here and Yonder and between the
two well like uh so sensuality sensual
pleasure is in the object yeah of the
senses yeah that's where it is and if I
just go towards it then I get it from
there into here out there into here yeah
yeah of course it is that division yeah
but the the whole idea like Whatever It
Is Well the whole idea like see you're
not seeing that when you thinking about
the central object that is already the
extent of the central object yeah and
the so then why would you have
subsequent actions towards it it's the
gratification cuz you realize well but
it's the extent of it that it can be
present it's already
present that is order its
gratification so following things
further with the body and on it's like
well that's completely
redundant that makes no
sense that requires you to not see it as
an
image to the extent that it has Arison
and then your actions seem to be gaining
and fulfilling and consuming the lack
what was
missing but if you see what's missing as
an image you realize well delighting in
what's missing is an image it's really
such missing is complete so to speak as an
missing is complete so to speak as an
image independent of space and time and
then it stops to imply the missing the
lack which means your Delight Fades
away so it's not
incidental that anagami
is free from sensuality and ill will
because both
require that extent
of the implication of another of that
Dimension that you getting to through
pursuing pleasure or expressing anger
but when that
seen real as such to Extended it has a
reason it has no no lack in itself and
that seen sufficiently and
repeatedly as I said any any actions any
assumptions that exist on account of
that assumed lack will will
disappear so you will not be able to get
angry you will not be able to to to get
get lustful and and drawn towards
the the attractive
form it requires personification
basically those actions require you to
personify the form that you perceive
which you are you start with
personification and you don't start
clean and then make a
mistake and when the form is De
personified here and
Yonder immediately reflexive it doesn't
matter when form is was basically when
image of form is seen as an image
understood to its
extent there can be no
disturbances arising in you CU any
disturbance that comes requires self
internally or externally or
both the as I said the the fear lust
desire loneliness
depression um any of
any of
these feelings and sort of complex Dukas
and so on it's all in relation to others
or seeing yourself as
yourself internal and external spaces
yeah private exactly private spaces
yeah and that's why hand he said for him
his actions or his entire being is as in
private so in public as in public so in
private absolutely no
discrepancy there's no
privacy there's no privacy but there is
no there is no private space but see
that also means there is no public space
either because public space is basically
private space of others that you are not
priv to that's why people fear the
Public Public Speaking exposure public
everybody looking at
me you you basically brings down it
reveals the gratuitously assumed
dimension of outside of yourself that
shows you your non-control but you're
assuming it through your control and you
don't see that and that's the
discrepancy felt when others are looking
at you and you feel you feel like put on
spot you're not seeing
the outside you're
experiencing as an image independent of
space and time independent of inside and
outside of here and
that and for that you are responsible so
see you are responsible for giving their
gratuitous power to that phenomenon of
outside point of
view you're giving power to it but that
phenomenon it shows you that you have no
power because it can go either way and
you know
that so that's why like it feels like
it's out of your hands but it's you're
doing so you
feel embarrassed even if you didn't do
anything wrong just by everybody
watching you your hands start to tremble
you can't speak all this you're
exposed it reveals the most deepest
personal assumption in regard to you
yourself that you have regarding
yourself yourself an outside point of view that
yourself an outside point of view that
in regard to yourself you feel protect
and hidden on the inside of me but it
just shows you that the same thing is
out there in regard to others and then
it reveals the inside of you that you
thought was safe cuz it wasn't
seen cuz you not seeing it if you were
to start seeing it you would be vomited
out it would be seen as an external
phenomenon
so when you think about for example your
mother she's absent from here she's out
there she's in South
Africa so you recognize the extent of
that thought you can see all that's a
thought but that
thought still
carries but that thought still carries
well still
implies that she is
the beting of her is out
there in South
Africa and how can you know
that how can that implication be
anything other than just another
peripheral image in regard to your
thoughts of your mother cuz she might
not be there her form might have been
disintegrated with a nuclear blast and
you're about to find out so she's
factually might not be
there the way you're thinking she is
there so it's probably
there but like but probability is all I
can have but probability are real as
such but whether your probability now
that probability
probability
implies the external space the world
where your mother
lives but then again that implication
will be there but you look at it
peripherally and see but that
implication when I'm thinking about my
mother is just another image
that's sure Less Direct less defined closer to
sure Less Direct less defined closer to
my point of view but again it's
manifested and whatever is manifested
it's neither here nor
Yonder it's a reason to the extent it
has a reason independent of space and
time space and time is second to
it and as such it's
impermanent see by undermining the
external Assumption of of the world the
matter that your mother lives in you're
undermining your own as
well and that's why people would be
afraid to do
it because you would feel it here and
now as
well so colloquially described see that
the peripheral thoughts images of the
possibilities of this and that doesn't
matter that appear really
such that that domain that's dependent
of space and time neither here no there
not in your head not in others it just
is to the extent that it is
that it's more real than your concrete
sense of being here this body
perceptions that come on account of it
all that and by more real I mean more
fundamental it's first
your concreteness here that you palpable
palpability of it all that is second to
it so now it's like okay so this
concreteness take it up feel that
physicality as I was saying and see the
phenomenality of
it see the peripheral image of it while
you're feeling it here and now and then
recognize it's the peripheral image of
it comes first while the physicality is
perceived
here so I'm experiencing something here
now doing this that drinking someone's
speaking all that
is secondary to the image of it of the
experience as a whole in regard to all
of those
specifics but see the image of the whole
the image as um of the experience as a
whole depends on the
specifics so it's not just I'll just
have these magical images and then
everything else follows out of them no
no you have two
domains domains of the specifics and
domains of the images of the experience
as a whole the actual the
peripheral simultaneously existing to
the extent they are it's like looking at
the same thing from two points of
view like imagine I don't know again
it's a poor example cuz
it's even three-dimensional cannot
convey the example because it depends on
space but I think I might have said this
before like I don't know imagine your
screen your laptop screen divided in half and
your laptop screen divided in half and
one is showing a view of the Earth
planet
Earth from the from the universe from
the space and the other one is showing
space and the other one is showing
some view of a camera on the street and
both are happening in real
time actually both are happening in real
time the events on the street are
happening within that Earth that you
that's watched from the high point of
view simultaneous one doesn't stop in
order for other to
arise and by the way that is actually
the contemplation of the the the great
elements how you undo your own little
measly sense of personified self form
here but recognizing oh I established my
mind upon the perception of Earth so
that anything inferior to it cannot
bother me see if your concerns now shift
onto the onto the image on the screen
that's that's that's the basically
planet earth viewed from the
space if you're concerned about what's
going to happen there is there an
asteroid coming stuff everything that's
happening live in real time simultaneous
on the street it's completely irrelevant
there was an argument over
uh pot of flowers between the neighbors
or something there was like raging mad
about to kill each other but now
suddenly your concern is on the level of
the element of planet
Earth simultanous still the argument
didn't stop it just becomes irrelevant
because you see there's something bigger
possibilities of something bigger could
occur and will occur and that's the
recognition it will break down so
everything here simultaneous to that not
in hindsight when I think about and and
convince myself that everything here is
irrelevant because the Earth is greatest
and it will come to pass and then no no
no simultaneous live feed of two points
of view
so there's a live feed going on
now in regard to your
experience and always has been
they were always two points of view
cannot be different it's just that
that Higher One put it that way it's
usually relegated and overburdened by
the concerns of the inferior one and and
sort of put second to that one so it
takes withdrawal from the concerns of
the inferior one through sense restraint
guarding of the sense doors all of
that to then shift the weight back and
then obviously until you eventually see
it and recognize that like as as I said
there's a live feed right now as we
speak we are factually on the planet
Earth as I'm saying we are on the planet
Earth there is a planet Earth that we
inhabit factually
so the image of of of of the planet
Earth that you have as an abstract thing
somewhere up there take it out of space
and time take it out of up there and see
it here factually living like the two
cameras providing simultaneous light
feed one from the earth one from what's
on Earth more specific
but it needs to be
simultaneous not like you go and then
you start reflecting and thinking about
the Earth and then you start applying
that here secondarily I mean you're
probably going to be doing that to some
extent but you have to recognize that
this can only be seen rightly if it's
simultaneously both both both of both
points of view are simultaneously
endured because if like you can't attend
to them to the same extent at the same
time one will be actual another will be
peripheral but it's whatever is then
seen as peripheral it's not
pushed into relegated notion of images
and possibilities as second to this but
is seen real such in dependent space and
time
simultaneous so think about the great
element of Earth is the live feed that's
happening now while you sit walk talk
eat
sleep as a necessary basis for you doing
all those inferior
actions air oxygen water heat on that
level of the Great hele great planet
Earth peripheral images but now
understood for what they are not assume
there's the outside space that I just
happened to inhabit and can afford to
forget about completely
about completely
seen and it pulls you out as I said of
that Assumption of internal private
space as well
cuz you realize there's nothing private
even your private internal sense of self
and personified space and the nobody's
private to is contained within the live feed of
to is contained within the live feed of
planet Earth it's it's contained within
it cannot be not there if you and your
form and everything else is on the
planet Earth all of your internal
concerns assumed internally also have to
be within that greater point of view of
the greater
perspective so it's nowhere to
hide and if that greater perspective
that great planet
Earth is seen rightly
as subject to
destruction Unown inconceivable to be owned or
Unown inconceivable to be owned or
controlled anything that's within
it it's exactly the the same and that's
when the Great external element of Earth
and so on and maab
budas start to pervade your internal
personified me private and is just seen
whether it's here or over there or even
on that highest level all he sees is
form externally he understands
it so his understanding of the form
externally ceases to be the Assumption
of the real form behind that
and to the extent that he he cognizes it
that's just what he
cognized and was it I think an quoted
that whether he thinks about the the
great Mountain mountains or or or his
his own body and everything associated
with it he sees there just
form
externally so it all becomes external in
that sense that it's
unable which is the property of
Pen's external when he thinks about see
the dimension of
others their private the Privacy that's
inaccessible to me the point of view
what they actually are that exists
outside of me that is
unable and that's why you fear it
obviously you can never possess it but
you don't see that what you're trying to
possess is another
image neither here nor there inde
dependent of space of
time that you gratuitously
allowed the implication that there is
the real behind which is another image
peripheral to that image and there is n
to
that and actually s did the whole I
think chapter on that how the being of
others always escapes you always slips
through fingers and it's unable and you
could dominate them to sadism or want to
be dominated to masochism I was
explaining all these psychological
categories but
that domain that that that sphere of
them it's completely always remains
inaccessible so all these things we try
to do kind of fall short to possess to
repossess yourself through possessing
others and whatever you're describing it
but failing to understand that that
doesn't matter how big is how far how
real my feel that they're real and
behind that is real such as an image
first not as an implication of the
outside
first but as I said that emphasis can
only be shifted through repeated
contemplation on the basis of right
instruction cuz if you have no reason no
no faith to keep repeating the same once
it will not undo the perverted
emphasis and you'll dismiss it
but even if you just approach it
logically how can it not be an image if
you're thinking it if you're subtly
aware of it how can well but no there is
the real outside behind well how can how
is that not an image now
simultaneity Double Life
feed and that's also another thing if
the if the if the two points of view are
always there simultaneously one cannot stand
there simultaneously one cannot stand
without the other even
even
exactly the the gratuitously elevated
assumed my one point of view gets even
out if there is two to the same extent
there can't be one in charge because
when one takes charge it's undermined by
the other that's looking at it from the
planet Earth Life
feed and if you start for whatever
reason mystified the planet Earth live
feed and not see the impermanence of
that well the immediate Life feed
arguing over a pot of flowers with
somebody reminds you of the impermanence
of that as
well CU if this little pathetic form
gets struck here well there will be no
more perception of the Earth planet
Earth life Fe either